

Turin, Italy +39 380 754 0657 mohamadusama242@gmail.com

Mohamad Usama KUNNATHUR

DevOps Engineer

https://github.com/usama242 https://www.linkedin.com/in/usama242/ https://kunnathur.live/

ABOUT

A DevOps and Cloud Engineer with more than two years of experience in building, automating and maintaining Cloud infrastructure and environment. A quick learner, team player, and multi-skilled (check the <u>website</u>) with an interest in Al. A background in Management & Engineering means I bring a unique perspective to the team.

SKILLS

Proficient: AWS (EC2, VPC, S3, SQS, SNS, etc), Python, JavaScript (NodeJS, TypeScript, etc), Linux, IaC (Cloudformation & Terraform), CI/CD (Bamboo, Gitlab, Azure Pipelines)

Moderate: Azure (VM, Pipeline, CLI, Policy, etc), Docker, Kubernetes, Postman, Selenium, Jmeter, Database (DynamoDB, MySQL, Elasticsearch, etc)

EXPERIENCE

Idea 75, Bari, Italy - DevOps Engineer

Oct 2022 - PRESENT

- Co-ordinating with a group of developers spanning different projects.
- Facilitate deployment automation and CI/CD. Monitoring and observability.
- Reduce bottlenecks (Build times, latency) and optimize costs (Rescaling resources)
- Ensure zero downtime and high availability (Load balancing & autoscaling resources)

Reply, Turin, Italy - Cloud Developer

MAY 2020 - OCT 2022

- Developed lambda functions and facilitated pipeline automation
- Troubleshooting and fixing the errors. Test automation (Functional, UI, Performance)
- Recommended redimensioning of resources saving \$10k / month

Associazione Erminio Bullio, Turin, Italy - Project Manager Intern

MAY 2020 - OCT 2022

- Primarily involved in Project Lifecycle Management of a construction project
- Developed custom modules in Odoo PLM software using Python

PROJECTS (BOSCH AI ACCELERATOR PROGRAM)

Deploying a scalable laaS web server in Azure (link)

- Using Terraform to create infrastructures like Virtual Networks, Virtual Machines, etc.
- Creating a custom VM Image using Packer then deploying it in VMs

Building a CI/CD pipeline (link)

- Cl using GitHub Actions to automate unit testing and linting to keep the code prod ready
- CD using Azure Pipelines which builds and deploys a Flask app to Azure App service

Ensuring quality releases (link)

- Automated testings like API (Postman), Functional UI (Selenium) & Performance (Jmeter)
- Also configuring Custom Log ingestion & Custom Alarm metrics.

Techtrends: Container Orchestration (link)

- Github actions to create a custom Docker image and push it to DockerHub
- Vagrant to provision a custom virtual machine environment in VirtualBox
- Deploy an app to a Kubernetes cluster using Helm chart & ArgoCD

Best coding practices and unit test (<u>link</u>)

- Refactoring a Jupyter notebook into a python code using best coding practices.
- This involves precise documentation, adhering to pep8 specs & unit tests.

EDUCATION

Bosch Al Talent Accelerator Program (Udacity, Online) - DevOps Engineer

JULY 2022 - NOV 2022

- Experienced infrastructure automation with hands-on projects.
- Followed clean code principles and focussed on cloud-native apps

Udacity, Online - Front-End Web Development

JAN 2020 - MAR 2020

- Focus on CSS, JavaScript, APIs, Build tools & Express. NodeJS for the backend.
- Front-end libraries such as React. The projects can be found in my <u>GitHub</u>

Politecnico di Torino, Turin, Italy - M.S Engineering & Management

SEP 2017 - MAR 2020

- Learnt about Information Systems, project and data management
- Thesis on "Applying A.I Techniques on Project management" (link)

THK University, Ankara, Turkey - B.S Aeronautical Engineering

SEP 2012 - JUNE 2016

- Concentration in Aerodynamics, FEM & CAD
- Academic internship on solving Navier-stokes equation using Python

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in the application to be processed for the purposes of recruitment/internal process